Lewis and Clark Journals 1803-1806 Mss.917.3.L58
American Philosophical Society
- Volume IV.
  - Codex M, 1 volume
    - Chopunnish Indian sketch map of Snake, Salmon, etc. rivers, 1806 May 28-31; 1 map, 40.6 x 12 cm; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 1-2)
      Realms of Gold, 28 (10).
    - Journal, 1806 Jun. 7-Aug. 14; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 3-145)
    - Weather diary, 1806 Jun.-Aug.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 146-152)
    - Memo of distances, n.d.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 154)
  - Codex N, 1 volume
    The volume follows normal pagination through page 85. After this, entries begin from the back and follow reverse pagination.
    - Memo of articles forwarded from St. Louis to Louisville, Kentucky, 1806; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 1-2)
    - Journal, 1806 Aug. 15-Sep. 26; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 3-78)
      - Meeting with a Native American chief, ca. 1806 Aug.-Sep. (Page 10)
    - Sketch of Ancient Fortification, 1806 Sep. 1; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 81-82)
      - Bon Homme Island on the Missouri River, 1806 Sep. 1 (Page 81)
      - Bon Homme Island on the Missouri River, 1806 Sep. 1 (Page 82)
    - Description of Ancient Fortification, n.d.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 83-85)
    - Botanical and zoological notes, Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 154-153)
    - Weather diary, 1806 Sep.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 152-151)
    - Clark's River to the Missouri-Medicine confluence, 1806 Jul. 3-11; 1 map, 40.6 x 12 cm; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 150-149)
      Realms of Gold, 28 (11).
    - Courses and distances from Travelers Rest Creek to Falls of Missouri, Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 148-144)
    - Summary of the statement of the rivers, etc., n.d.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 142-133)
    - Summary statement of the Yellowstone, 1806; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 132-131)
    - Portage from Yellowstone to 3 Forks, n.d.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 130-129)
    - Various notes, n.d.; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 128-122)
  - Codex O, 1 volume
    - Description of astronomical instruments, 1804 Jul. 22; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 1-6)
    - Astronomical observations, 1804 May 18-1805 Mar. 30; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 6-52)
      - Point of observation no. 14, 1804 Jun. 27 (Page 7)
    - Summary view of rivers and creeks from the mouth of the Missouri upward, 1806 June 9; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 69-128)
- Volume V.
  - Codex P, 1 volume
    The volume follows normal pagination through page 124. After this, entries begin from the back and follow reverse pagination.
    - Memo of weather, 1804 Feb. 28-Mar. 28; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page flyleaf and 1)
    - Description of astronomical instruments, 1804 Jul. 22; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 1-6)
    - Memo of Jefferson deposit, Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844 (Page 1)
    - Various zoological and botanical notes, 1805 Apr. 9-1806 Feb. 17; Unidentified (Page 13-124)
    - Money accounts, cancelled, 1804; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page flyleaf)
    - Miscellaneous memo, n.d.; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 133)
    - Weather diary, 1805 Jul.-Sep.; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 131-125)
  - Codex Q, 1 volume
    - Natural history notes, 1804 Aug. 2-1805 May 9; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 4-56)
    - Natural history notes, 1804-1806; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 57-181)
  - Codex R, 1 volume
    - Memo of Jefferson deposit (torn), Biddle, Nicholas, 1786-1844 (Page 2)
    - Botanical register: list of plants no. 1-108, 1804 May 10-Nov. 17; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 4-49)
      - "Convolvalist" leaf (Convulvulus sepium, hedge bindweed), 1804 Jul. 17 (Page 37)
    - Zoological notes, Fort Clatsop, 1805 Dec. 18; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 50-53)
    - Botanical and zoological notes, Fort Clatsop, 1806 Feb. 18-Mar. 11; Clark, William, 1770-1838 (Page 59-162)
    - Memo of "lava", n.d.; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 163)
    - Word "mineralogy" and memo of a bird, Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page inside back cover)
  - Codex S, 1 paper enclosure
    - Rough draft of letter to Thomas Jefferson annoucing return of the Expedition to St. Louis., 1806 Sep. 23; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 1-11)
    - Rough draft of letter to Thomas Jefferson (partial), 1806 Sep. 21; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 (Page 12-16)
  - Codex T, 1 paper enclosure
    - Fragment describing journey, n.d.; Unidentified (Page 12-16)
- Volume VI.
  - Diary, 1804 Jan.1-1805 Apr. 9; 1 volume; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809 and Clark, William, 1770-1838
    Contains meterological observations and accounts of distances traveled.
    - Abbreviations of weather and river observations, 1804 Jan. 1 (Page 1-2)
- Volume VII.
  - A list of the names of the different nations and tribes of Indian inhabiting the country on the Missouria..., 1 large sheet; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    - Obverse, n.d. (Page obverse)
    - Reverse, n.d. (Page reverse)
  - Estimate of the Western Indians, 4 pages; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    The reverse of page 1 features a draft of the map that appears in Codex N:81-82.
  - Receipts of deposit of Lewis and Clark material to the American Philosophical Society, 1818; 5 pages; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
  - Letter requesting to borrow the journals to prepare a new edition of the "Travels of Lewis and Clark.", 1892 Dec. 16; 5 pages; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
  - The Fisher, n.d.; 1 sketch; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
- Volume VIII.
  - The country and rivers in advance or above the Mandans, 1805; 2 pages; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    Cf. Codex O:117-118
  - A slight view of the Missouri River, n.d.; 4 pages; Clark, William, 1770-1838
  - A summary statement of the river and creeks which fall into the Missouri, 12 pages; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    Cf. Codex O:69-116
  - Multonomah River (fragment), n.d.; 1 map, 35.6 x 9.5 cm; Clark, William, 1770-1838
    Realms of Gold, 28 (12).
  - A description of the Indian nations, 4 pages; Clark, William, 1770-1838
  - A statistical view of the Indian nations inhabiting the territory of Louisiana and the countries adjacent, 1 page; Clark, William, 1770-1838
  - [Handwritten transcription] Extracts from Capt. McKay's journal with notes by John Hay., 12 pages; Captain McKay and John Hay
  - Memorandum replying to questions of Nicholas Biddle, 1 page; Clark, William, 1770-1838
  - Memoranda pertaining to the expedition., 2 pages; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809
    Contains notes on several Indian nations. Originally found in Ordway's Journal, volume 2 (917.3 Or2)
- Volume IX.
  - Donation book containing a list of dried leaves etc. collected in the far West by Merriwether Lewis, n.d.; 1 paperbound volume; Lewis, Meriwether, 1774-1809
    collected in the far west. List of specimens, boxed, Jan.11, 1884, at the A.P.S. by Michael Carraher, in envelope in front of book.